Mikko Kurkela

Address: Kiviniementie 3 as 3

96400 Rovaniemi, Finland

Phone: +358 442 800 489

Email: mikko.sahkoposti@gmail.com

Website: mkurkela.github.io

OBJECTIVE

A position in the field of information technology. I got good knowledge on Linux operating system and C/C++ programming languages. I have been working with profiling software and dealt with x86 and ARM assembly language.

I am also interested on networking and network security. During my studies I have done CCNA networking courses.

I am not too picky on what kind of job I am doing as long as I can learn new things and get more experience.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering, Information Technology

Rovaniemi University of Applied Sciences, expected May 2013

Concentration: Software development

Bachelor Thesis, Attaching the IgProf Profiler into a Running Process on a 64-bit Linux

The thesis described a method to attach the IgProf profiler software into a running process by making the target process to execute function calls, which loaded necessary environment variables and loaded the IgProf shared object into the address space of the target process

Aliupseerikoulu,2008–2009 Jääkäriprikaati, Sodankylä

Ylioppilastutkinto, 2004–2007 Ounasvaaran urheilulukio

COMPUTER SKILLS

Languages: C, C++, x86 assembly, ARM assembly, C#, Java, PHP

Operating Systems: Linux

Networking: I have done CCNA networking courses

EXPERIENCE

Software developer

April 2013 – Present

CERN, The European Organization for Nuclear research, Geneve, Swizerland

Main task was to port the IgProf profiler software for ARM processor. I also got other IgProf related programming tasks.

- Ported the IgProf profiler software for ARM processors
- Miscellanous programming tasks with C and C++ programming languages related to the IgProf profiling software

Practical Training: Software Developer June 2012 – September 2012 CERN, The European Organization for Nuclear research, Geneve, Swizerland

Miscellanous programmin tasks related to the IgProf profiling software. For example x86_64 instruction length decoder and IgProf function profiler and finstrumented-functions profiling modules.

Skiresort worker Spring 2009

Ounasvaaran Hiihtokeskus, Rovaniemi, Finland

I worked in lift control and in slope maintaining in Ounasvaara ski-resort

MILITARY SERVICE

I did my military service in 2008–2009 in Jääkäriprikaati in Sodankylä. The serving duration was 362 days.

LANGUAGE SKILLS

- Finnish, native
- English, Good, Bachelor degree done in english
- Swedish, Average, Understanding is good but I have never had to use swedish so oral skills would need some practicing
- German, Basics, I can translate basic sentences

INTERESTS

- Sports
- Computer Security
- Guitar
- MMO computer games